Guide to the Lassiter Family Papers, 1832-1928
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lassiter Family papers 1832-1928
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Lassiter Family
29 linear feet Extent: 21,752 Items
Daniel William Lassiter was a physician of Petersburg, Va. Collection comprises correspondence and other papers of Daniel William Lassiter, and of his sons, Francis Rives Lassiter, lawyer and U.S. Representative from Virginia, and Charles Trotter Lassiter, politician. Much of the correspondence concerns the political career of Francis R. Lassiter. Includes information on Confederate recruitment, politicians after the Civil War, Presidential elections, the Virginia militia, and economic conditions in the U.S. Correspondents include Henry Mills Alden, Thomas Baily Aldrich, John Hollis Bankhead, Harry Flood Byrd, Champ Clark, John Warwick Daniel, Henry De La War Flood, Carter Glass, Epps Hunton, Jr., Fitzhugh Lee, Arthur Lefevre, William Gordon McCabe, Thomas Staples Martin, John Garland Pollard, Furnifold McLendel Simmons, Charles Augustus Swanson, Henry St. George Tucker, Lyon Gardiner Tyler, and Edward Carrington Venable.
RL.00798
Language: Material in English
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Lassiter Family Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library from 1949-1951.
Collection Overview
Collection comprises correspondence and other papers of Daniel William Lassiter, and of his sons, Francis Rives Lassiter, lawyer and U.S. Representative from Virginia, and Charles Trotter Lassiter, politician. Much of the correspondence concerns the political career of Francis R. Lassiter. Includes information on Confederate recruitment, politicians after the Civil War, Presidential elections, the Virginia militia, and economic conditions in the U.S. Correspondents include Henry Mills Alden, Thomas Baily Aldrich, John Hollis Bankhead, Harry Flood Byrd, Champ Clark, John Warwick Daniel, Henry De La War Flood, Carter Glass, Epps Hunton, Jr., Fitzhugh Lee, Arthur Lefevre, William Gordon McCabe, Thomas Staples Martin, John Garland Pollard, Furnifold McLendel Simmons, Charles Augustus Swanson, Henry St. George Tucker, Lyon Gardiner Tyler, and Edward Carrington Venable.
Subject Headings
Lassiter, Daniel William, 1827-1903; Lassiter, Charles Trotter, b. 1870; Lassiter, Francis Rives, 1866-1907; Lassiter family; Confederate States of America. Army -- Recruiting, enlistment, etc.; Virginia. Militia; Lawyers -- Virginia -- Correspondence; Presidents -- United States -- Election; United States -- Economic conditions; United States -- Politics and government -- 1901-1909; Virginia -- Politics and government -- 1865-1950
Contents of Collection
- Charles T. Lassiter Series, 1892-1928 and undated, (19 boxes)
  - 1892-1895 Mar. 31 (Box 1)
  - 1895 Apr.-1897 Apr. 10 (Box 2)
  - 1897 Apr. 12- 1899 Dec. 31 (Box 3)
  - 1901 Jan. 1-1902 Aug. 20 (Box 4)
  - 1902 Aug. 21-1903 Aug. 15 (Box 5)
  - 1903 Aug. 17-1904 July 20 (Box 6)
  - 1904 July 21-1905 July 20 (Box 7)
  - 1905 July 21-1907 Dec. 31 (Box 8)
  - 1908 Jan. 1-1909 Feb. 20 (Box 9)
  - 1909 Feb. 22-Apr. 30 (Box 10)
  - 1909 May 1-Nov. 19 (Box 11)
  - 1909 Nov. 20-Dec. 31 (Box 12)
  - 1910 Jan. 15-Feb. 28 (Box 13)
  - 1910 Mar. 1-1914 (Box 14)
  - 1915-1919 (Box 15)
  - 1920-1924 (Box 16)
  - 1925-1927 (Box 17)
  - 1928 and undated (Box 18)
  - Undated (Box 19)
- Daniel W. Lassiter Series, 1832-1908, (1 box)
  - Papers, 1832-1908 (Box 20)
- Francis R. Lassiter Series, 1879-1909 and undated, (33 boxes)
  - 1879-1889 Apr. 30 (Box 21)
  - 1889 May 1-1890 Dec. 31 (Box 22)
  - 1891-1892 (Box 23)
  - 1893 Jan. 1-Sept. 30 (Box 24)
  - 1893 Oct. 1-1894 May 31 (Box 25)
  - 1894 June 1-1895 Mar. 20 (Box 26)
  - 1895 Mar. 21-Oct. 9 (Box 27)
  - 1895 Oct. 9-1896 May 31 (Box 28)
  - 1896 June 1-Nov.3 (Box 29)
  - 1896 Nov. 4-1897 Apr. 30 (Box 30)
  - 1897 May 1-July 20 (Box 31)
  - 1897 July 21-Oct. 15 (Box 32)
  - 1897 Oct. 16-1898 July 31 (Box 33)
  - 1898 Aug. 1-1899 Apr. 15 (Box 34)
  - 1899 Apr. 17-1900 Mar. 10 (Box 35)
  - 1900 Mar. 11-May 31 (Box 36)
  - 1900 June 1-Sept. 30 (Box 37)
  - 1900 Oct. 1-Dec. 20 (Box 38)
  - 1900 Dec. 21-1901 Feb. 28 (Box 39)
  - 1901 Mar. 1-Aug. 20 (Box 40)
  - 1901 Aug. 21-1902 Jan. 11 (Box 41)
  - 1902 Jan. 13-Mar. 24 (Box 42)
  - 1902 Mar. 25-May 25 (Box 43)
  - 1902 May 26-Dec. 31 (Box 44)
  - 1903 Jan. 1-1905 Dec. 31 (Box 45)
  - 1906 Jan. 1-June 30 (Box 46)
  - 1906 July 1-1908 Feb. 28 (Box 47)
  - 1908 Mar. 1-May 15 (Box 48)
  - 1908 May 16-Oct. 31 (Box 49)
  - 1908 Nov. 1-1909 Jan. 31 (Box 50)
  - 1909 Feb. 1-Apr. 10 (Box 51)
  - 1909 Apr. 11-July 31 (Box 52)
  - 1909 Aug. 1-Dec. 31 and undated (Box 53)
- Manuscript Volumes Series
  - For locations of volumes L:2186, F:2185, and F:2184, please consult with a reference archivist. (Box 53)